

# **VITOR PRADO**

MOBILE & BACKEND DEVELOPER

SAO PAULO, BRAZIL

**1** +55 (11) 98862-8233

□ VITORPRADO.DEV

□

#### **EDUCATION**

TECHNICAL SCHOOL OF UNICAMP CERTIFICATE IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT 01/2010 - 12/2011

## MOBILE DEVELOPMENT

#### **SENIOR**

JAVA KOTLIN SWIFT

KOTLIN MULTIPLATFORM

REACT NATIVE

SERVER DRIVEN UI

UNIT TESTING

CI/CD

#### **BACKEND DEVELOPMENT**

#### **SENIOR**

RUBY

IAVASCRIPT/TYPESCRIPT

NODEJS

POSTGRESQL

APIS

UNIT TESTING

# **LANGUAGES**

PORTUGUESE (NATIVE SPEAKER) ENGLISH (ADVANCED)

#### **INTERESTS**

MUSIC CYCLING COOKING

### **SUMMARY**

I'm a Mobile and Backend developer based in Brazil with solid experience building entire systems from scratch. I've been working with code since 2012, helping businesses to solve their problems through technology. I have already worked with Android, iOS, Ruby, JavaScript/TypeScript, React Native, and KMM (Kotlin Multiplatform).

## **EXPERIENCE**

LAUNDRO

12/2021 - 11/2022

LEAD SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I built the whole technology stack of the company. Even though I wasn't at the beginning of the app's development, when I joined the company, the only existing code was a real-time database built using Firebase. I implemented TypeScript and AdonisJS to create a new API and to deliver a full-featured server capable of handling payments and integrating with multiple external applications (for partners), as well as a set of tools for the operations team. Afterward, I rewrote the app to make it capable of using the new APIs and native payments.

- Responsible for whole tech stack
- TypeScript
- React Native
- AdonisJS
- PostgreSQL

- Redis
- Heroku
- Unit Testing
- TDD
- CI/CD

#### **WORLDPACKERS**

SENIOR ANDROID DEVELOPER

I worked as the leading Android Developer, improving two apps (travelers and hosts). I led the migration of the host's app to Kotlin Multiplatform and the modern view systems (Compose and SwiftUI). Meanwhile, occasionally I helped the web development team with Ruby on Rails tasks and bug fixes.

- Android
- lava
- Kotlin
- iOS
- Swift
- Kotlin Multiplatform
- Compose

- SwiftUI
- Ruby on Rails
- Heroku
- Unit Testing
- TDD
- CI/CD

#### **INGRESSO RAPIDO**

10/2016 - 10/2017

01/2014 - 10/2016

06/2018 - 12/2021

SENIOR ANDROID DEVELOPER

I worked as an Android Developer, responsible for the ticket reader app used in concerts and theaters to validate tickets. I delivered a way to minimize fraud using local broadcasts on the intranet and the ability to use a USB barcode scanner attached to an Android device to increase speed in operations.

- Android
- lava

Kotlin

# **GRUPO VERISOFT**

SENIOR ANDROID DEVELOPER

I worked as Main Android Developer, building white-label applications for mobile carriers. We made a Ferrari sticker album app used by Claro (a mobile carrier) in Mexico. For a few months, I was the only one developing "Vivo TreinApp" on the web, an internal web app used by Vivo (a mobile carrier) to train employees.

Android

Ruby on Rails

Java

#### **PINUTS STUDIOS**

02/2013 - 01/2014

ANDROID DEVELOPER

Pinuts was an outsourcing company focused on the mobile market. The company hired me as a Rails developer, but then switched to Android Developer after the

first month.

AndroidRuby on Rails

TDDCI/CD

Unit Testing

MENKI GAMES

01/2012 - 01/2013

DEVELOPMENT INTERN

I joined Menki as an intern to develop mobile games using Lua & CoronaSDK. I have acquired extensive knowledge about Lua, Ruby on Rails, APIs, and Android native.

LuaCoronaSDKAndroidRuby on Rails

# **PUBLICATIONS**

## JETC.DEV NEWSLETTER ISSUE #55

03/2021

JETC.DEV ☑

I was featured in "Jetc.dev", an important newsletter from the Jetpack Compose community, about a rating bar library I've made.